Sritrusta Sukaridhoto

CTO, Technology Enthusiast and Guitarist

contact biography



PT. Solusi Integra Indonesia Beltway Office Park, Tower B 5th Floor Jl. T.B. Simatupang No. 41 Jakarta, 12550 - Indonesia

Mobile:+62 823 6666 6379 Email: s.dhoto@solusiintegra.co.id

> Dhoto's Homepage Google Scholar Scopus-ID git://iseng4h fb://iseng4h

languages

Indonesian (native) English & Japanese

research interests

Computer Networks, Human-centric, Multimedia & Internet of Things



Received the B.E. degree in electrical engineering, computer science program from Sepuluh Nopember Institute of Technology, Indonesia, in 2002 and the Ph.D. degree in Communication Networks Engineering from Okayama University, Japan, in 2013. He joined PT. Solusi Integra Indonesia as Chief Technology Officer in 2019. Before, He also a lecturer at Politeknik Elektronika Negeri Surabaya, Indonesia, from 2002. From 2017, He becomes Head of Human Centric Multimedia Lab, received several research grants, and also has several collaborations with government and industries. He is a technology enthusiast, his

research interests include computer networks, human-centric, immersive multimedia technology, and Industrial Internet of Things. He hold CertNexus Certified IoT Practitioner, ISO27001 lead auditor and received several awards, including IEEE Young Researcher Award in 2009. While in the free time, He love to play a guitar.

education

2009–2013 **Doctor** of Philosophy

Engineering

Dissertation: "A Study of Performance Improvement Methods for Real-Time Applications in Wireless Mesh Networks"

Supervised by Prof. Nobuo Funabiki, Prof. M. Hata and Prof. Toru Nakanishi

1997-2002 Bachelor of Engineering

Institut Teknologi Sepuluh Nopember, Indonesia

Electrical Engineering - Computer Science

Thesis: "Implementation of IPv6 in Institute Technology Sepuluh November of Surabaya"

Supervised by Dr. Surva Sumpeno and Dr. Supeno Mardi

work experience

2019-now PT. Solusi Integra Indonesia

BSD. Indonesia

Chief technology officer, startup that working on solution and integration in the field of oil and gas, manufacture, and IT.

2002-Now Politeknik Elektronika Negeri Surabaya

Surabaya, Indonesia

Okayama University, Japan

Assistant Professor & Head of Lab

- Graduate School of Information Technology,
 - * Teaching: Advanced Computer Networks and Internet of Things
 - * Supervision of Master students
- Department of Multimedia Creative Technology,
 - * Teaching: Data Communication and Computer Networks
 - * Supervision of Undergraduate students

CV-Dhoto - Page 1 of 7

Head of Human Centric Multimedia Lab

2019-2021 Dinas Kependudukan dan Catatan Sipil

IT Consultant

2017, 2018 Bank Jatim

IT Consultant

Surabaya, Indonesia

Surabaya, Indonesia

2018 Artha Patria - Softwate Development

Surabaya, Indonesia

CTO, we develop software for human resource management. Our clients: PT. Quantum, Inasgoc2018, BPKH, etc

2015-2018 UGT Sidogiri - USAT

Pasuruan, Indonesia

Internet Service Provider Consultant

2017, 2018 PT. Eyro Digital Technology

Surabaya, Indonesia

IoT, Big Data architecture Consultant

2016 Dinas Komunikasi dan Informatika

Surabaya, Indonesia

Network Security Consultant

2014, 2019 PT PAL SURABAYA - Kementrian Pertahanan dan Keamanan RI Okpo,

Korea

Research and Development of National Submarine Transfer of Technology, national research collaboration and Submarine design for weapon system, communication, and computer system

2004-2009 Politeknik Elektronika Negeri Surabaya

Surabaya, Indonesia

CISCO Network Academy Instructor

1999-2002 Institut Teknologi Sepuluh Nopember

Surabaya, Indonesia

Network Administrator of its.ac.id, manage all network devices such as switches, routers and servers.

1999-2002 Judistira Webhosting

Surabaya, Indonesia

Network Administrator of web hosting provider, manage all servers and web developer

research experience

2017-Now Human Centric Multimedia

Surabaya, Indonesia

Head of Lab

Research about Multimedia and Internet of Things

- Augmented and Virtual Reality
- Human-Centric, Interaction with Computer Vision and Speech Recognition-Understanding
- Internet of Things and BigData
- Application of Machine Learning and Artificial Intelligence

2013-2017 EEPIS Robotics Research Center (ER2C)

Surabaya, Indonesia

Senior Researcher

Research about Cyber-Physical Systems

- MicroKernel OS for Embedded System

- Human Robot Interaction with Computer Vision and Speech Recognition-Understanding
- Internet of Things and BigData

2008-2013 Distributed System Lab, Okayama University

Okayama, Japan

Research Assistant under supervised by Prof. Nobuo Funabiki Research about Communication Networks

- Wireless Mesh Networks
- Real-time wireless communication
- Mac protocol

2004-2008 Computer Network Units of EEPIS

Surabaya, Indonesia

Research on

- Computer Networks
- Computer Vision and Speech Recognition
- Integrity Systems

2003-2004 Tohoku University

Sendai, Japan

Visiting Reseacher under supervised by Prof. Takafumi Aoki Research on

- Biometric Fingerprint Matching
- Parallel Computing
- Embedded System

award and certification

2020 Exin Agile Scrum Master

EXIN

Credential Link

2020 Exin Agile Scrum Foundation

EXIN

Credential Link

2020 AgilePM Foundation

APMG International

Credential Link

2020 ISO27001 Lead Auditor - Information Security Certification

Intertek

ID: 211206

2020 CertNexus Certified Internet of Things Practioner (CIOTP)

CertNexus

2020 Pro Tools Certified User

AVID

Credential link

Credential link

2019 Best Paper Award

IES2019, Indonesia

Designing of a Smart Collar for Dairy Cow Behavior Monitoring with Application Monitoring in Microservices and Internet of Things-Based Systems, Yogi Putra Pratama, Dwi Kurnia Basuki, Sritrusta Sukaridhoto, Alviansyah Arman Yusuf, Heri Yulianus, Faruq Faruq, Fariz Bramasta Putra; (2019 International Electronics Symposium (IES)), Indonesia

2018 Best Paper Award

TELKOMNIKA. Indonesia

Implementation Integration of VaaMSN with SEMAR for Air Monitoring Solution, Yohanes Yohanie Fridelin Panduman, Adnan Rachmat Anom Besari, Sritrusta Sukaridhoto, Rizqi Putri Nourma Budiarti, Rahardhita Widyatra Sudibyo, Funabiki Nobuo; TELKOMNIKA (Telecommunication Computing Electronics and Control), Indonesia

2013-2016 **Dosen Joss**

Politeknik Elektronika Negeri Surabaya

Annual award for the best lecturer in department.

2014 **Best Paper Award** The 16th International Electronics Symposium, Indonesia Application Programming Interface Design of Microkernel Based Robotics Operating System, Adhe Widianjaya, Dadet Pramadihanto, Sritrusta Sukaridhoto; The 16th International Electronics Symposium, Indonesia

2009 IEEE's Young Researcher Award

ISCE2009, Japan

2009 Monbusho Scholarship for Doctoral Program

Okayama University, Japan

2008 CCNA Certified

CISCO

CISCO ID: CSCO11381768

2007 **Best Paper Award** Seminar Nasional Open-Source Software ke-2, Indonesia "Sistem Pendeteksi Gambar Porno", Dadet Pramadihanto, Sritrusta Sukaridhoto, Muhammad Fatoni A, Rudy Cahyadi H; Prosiding Seminar Nasional Open Source Software ke-2 2007

intellectual property rights

2018 ALAT MONITORING KONDISI MOBIL SECARA REAL TIME BERBASIS INTERNET OF THINGS (IOTs)

Patent

ID: S00201806038

2018 V-Health Rest (Vehicle Health Report Assistant) – Teknologi Mobil Pintar Untuk Meningkatkan Service Dan Security Menuju Indonesia Smart City

Copyright

ID: EC00201806826

2018 PROGRAM KOMPUTER SISTEM MONITORING KONDISI MOBIL PADA ECU MOBYDIC 4910 SECARA REAL-TIME BERBASIS INTERNET OF THINGS

Copyright

ID: EC00201807850

research grants

2020 Implementasi Vehicle as a Mobile Sensor Network terintegrasi dengan Smart Environment Monitoring and Analytics in Real-time (SEMAR) system sebagai Pemantau Permukaan Jalan dan Lingkungan untuk mendukung Smart City

Penelitian Terapan Unggulan Perguruan Tinggi (Lead) - year: 3 of 3 - Rp. 143.310.000,-

	Penelitian Terapan Unggulan Perguruan Tinggi - year	: 3 of 3 - Rp. 132.860.000,-
2019	Implementasi Vehicle as a Mobile Sensor Network Smart Environment Monitoring and Analytics in system sebagai Pemantau Permukaan Jalan da mendukung Smart City Penelitian Terapan Unggulan Perguruan Tinggi (Lea 143.310.000,-	Real-time (SEMAR) n Lingkungan untuk
2019	Implementasi Teknologi Portable Ubiquitous He gan Layanan Cloud Untuk Mendukung Smart He sia Penelitian Terapan Unggulan Perguruan Tinggi - year	ealth Buatan Indone-
2019	INTELIGENT SYSTEM DEVELOPMENT FOR AUCATION OF FRUIT DEFECT Penelitian Kompetitif Nasional (PPS-PTM) - year: 1 c	DIKTI
2018	Implementasi Vehicle as a Mobile Sensor Network Smart Environment Monitoring and Analytics in system sebagai Pemantau Permukaan Jalan dal mendukung Smart City Penelitian Terapan Unggulan Perguruan Tinggi (Lea 120.000.000,-	Real-time (SEMAR) n Lingkungan untuk
2018	Implementasi Teknologi Portable Ubiquitous He gan Layanan Cloud Untuk Mendukung Smart He sia Penelitian Terapan Unggulan Perguruan Tinggi (Me Rp. 120.000.000,-	ealth Buatan Indone-
2018	Revitalisasi Sistem Jejaring Radio HF Untuk Metasi Jejaring Radio Pemerintah – GRN Penelitian Terapan Unggulan Perguruan Tinggi (MeRp. 130.000.000,-	DIKTI
2018	Pusat Pendidikan dan Pelatihan Embedded Systebagai Upaya Penyiapan Sumber Daya Manusia Me Ekonomi ASEAN Ipteks Bagi Inovasi Kreativitas Kampus (Member) - ye + Rp 50.000.000,-	enjelang Masyarakat DIKTI
2018	Industrial Edge Computing inKind	CISCO System Indonesia
2018	Industrial Internet of Things inKind	Ichii Industries Indonesia
2018	IoT - Smartglass for Industrial Factory Assistant inKind	TMMIN
	C	V-Dhoto - Page 5 of 7

2020 Implementasi Teknologi Portable Ubiquitous Health (U-Health) Dengan Layanan Cloud Untuk Mendukung Smart Health Buatan Indone-

2017	DESIG	GN A	AND	DEVE	LO	PMEN	T C	F U	NM	INA	IED	UN	DEF	RWATE	ER \	√EHI-
	CLES	FOI	R EN	VIRO I	NME	NTAL	. MC	CINC	ΓOR	RING	i AN	D D	ATA	ACQ	JISI	TION
	COME	PATI	BLE	WITH	5D	WOR	LD	MA	P S	YST	EM	IN I	INTE	RNET	OF	UN-
	DERV	VATI	ER T	HINGS	3											DIKT
	D 1															

Penelitian Kerjasama Luar Negeri dan Publikasi International - year: 3 of 3 - Rp. 151.000.000,-

2017 Pusat Pendidikan dan Pelatihan Embedded System Bersertifikasi Sebagai Upaya Penyiapan Sumber Daya Manusia Menjelang Masyarakat Ekonomi ASEAN

Ipteks Bagi Inovasi Kreativitas Kampus - year: 2 of 3 - Rp. 189.000.000,-+ Rp 50.000.000,-

2017 Industrial Internet of Things inKind

Ichii Industries Indonesia

2017 CSR for Robotics and IoT inKind

TMMIN

2016 DESIGN AND DEVELOPMENT OF UNMANNED UNDERWATER VEHI-CLES FOR ENVIRONMENTAL MONITORING AND DATA ACQUISITION COMPATIBLE WITH 5D WORLD MAP SYSTEM IN INTERNET OF UN-DERWATER THINGS

Penelitian Kerjasama Luar Negeri dan Publikasi International - year: 2 of 3 - Rp. 160.000.000,-

2016 Pusat Pendidikan dan Pelatihan Embedded System Bersertifikasi Sebagai Upaya Penyiapan Sumber Daya Manusia Menjelang Masyarakat Ekonomi ASEAN

Ipteks Bagi Inovasi Kreativitas Kampus - year: 1 of 3 - Rp. 189.000.000,-+ Rp 50.000.000,-

2015 DESIGN AND DEVELOPMENT OF UNMANNED UNDERWATER VEHI-CLES FOR ENVIRONMENTAL MONITORING AND DATA ACQUISITION COMPATIBLE WITH 5D WORLD MAP SYSTEM IN INTERNET OF UN-DERWATER THINGS

Penelitian Kerjasama Luar Negeri dan Publikasi International - year: 1 of 3 - Rp. 157.500.000,-

2015 Virtual Reality Lab sebagai penunjang Perkuliahan Terbuka Jarak Jauh (PTJJ) Seamolec

Penelitian Hibah PTJJ Seamolec - Rp 10.000.000,-

2014 PENGEMBANGAN ARSITEKTUR KOMPUTASI DAN SISTEM OPERASI ROBOTIKA UNTUK PENINGKATAN DAYA SAING APLIKASI ROBOTIKA NASIONAL

Penelitian Unggulan Perguruan Tinggi - year: 2 of 5 - Rp 200.000.000,-

2005 Rancang Bangun Prototype Mesin Verifikasi Sidik Jari Compact and Mobile dengan Algoritma Phase-Only Correlation Berbasis Embedded System

Penelitian Hibah Bersaing - Rp 40.000.000,-

2005 Studi dan Penerapan Teknologi Biometric Fingerprint Matching – Phase Only Correlation Pada Embedded System
Penelitian Dosen Muda - Rp 10.000.000,-

interests

research: computer networks, embedded system, multimedia & Internet of Things **personal:** play guitar, read comics, have fun with my kids

signature

The fully truth of the details are guaranteed. With strong sense of responsibility, hands on management and communication skills. Strong loyalty and self-motivation.

regards,

Sritrusta Sukaridhoto, ST. Ph.D.